In this video, we're going to step through the process of designing an algorithm in
在本视频中，我们将逐步介绍在
the context of the following problem.
以下问题的背景下设计算法的过程。
Here we have a 16x16 grid and we're interested in drawing a blue rectangle of
这里我们有一个 16x16 的网格，我们想画一个
particular height and width located at a particular starting x, y location.
位于特定起点 x, y 位置的特定高度和宽度的蓝色矩形。
So to begin with, we'll just look at a specific instance of this problem.
因此，首先，我们只看一下这个问题的一个具体实例。
Let's suppose that the starting point should have the x and y coordinates (7,9).
假设起点应该有 x 和 y 坐标 (7,9)。
The width of the rectangle should be 8 and the height of the rectangle should be 4.
矩形的宽度应为 8，矩形的高度应为 4。
Now, to do an instance of the problem,
现在，为了举一个问题实例，
we're going to look at our starting point and simply draw that rectangle.
我们要看看我们的起点，然后简单地画出那个矩形。
You can assume that you have some kind of a blue pen and
你可以假设你有一支蓝笔，
you are just going to draw this rectangle as the problem specified.
你只想按照指定的问题画这个矩形。
Now we need to take a step back and write down what we just did.
现在我们需要退后一步，写下我们刚才所做的事情。
The first thing that we did was start at point (7,9) and
我们做的第一件事是从点（7,9）开始，
draw a horizontal line the length of 8.
画一条长度为8的水平线。
Next, we draw another horizontal line of length 8 starting at (7,10).
接下来，我们画另一条长度为 8 的水平线，从 (7,10) 开始。
A third horizontal line that starts one point higher.
第三条水平线，起点高一点。
And finally, a fourth horizontal line starting at (7,12).
最后，第四条水平线从 (7,12) 开始。
Let's step away from the drawing and
让我们离开绘图，
look at the actual lines we've written out, describing what we did.
看看我们写出的实际线条，描述我们的所作所为。
You'll notice that this is a very repetitive process.
你会注意到这是一个非常重复的过程。
The only difference in these four steps is the y coordinate.
这四个步骤中唯一的区别是 y 坐标。
The y coordinate starts at 9 and stops at 12.
y 坐标从 9 开始，在 12 处停止。
The reason that we start at 9 is because that's the starting
我们之所以从 9 开始，是因为这是
y coordinate of our rectangle.
矩形的起始 y 坐标。
The reason we stop at 12 is because we're interested in drawing a rectangle but
我们之所以在 12 点停下来，是因为我们有兴趣画一个矩形，但
has height 4.
高度为 4。
So, we're going to draw four horizontal lines stopping at y + height- 1.
因此，我们将画四条水平线，停在 y + height-1 处。
Now, that we've inspected these four steps,
现在，我们已经检查了这四个步骤，
let's try to write an algorithm that will generalize them.
让我们尝试编写一个可以概括它们的算法。
Recall that we were counting up from y to the value y + height.
回想一下，我们从 y 向上计数到 y + 高度值。
Now, this was actually an exclusive y + height, because we counted 9, 10, 11, 12.
现在，这实际上是 y + 的专有高度，因为我们数了 9、10、11、12。
We did not actually go all the way up to 13, which is y+height.
实际上，我们并没有一路走到 13，也就是 y+height。
We're going to call this number i, and then for each of those values, we're going
我们要把这个数字叫做 i，然后对于每个值，我们
to draw a horizontal line of length 8, starting at the coordinate (7,i).
要画一条长度为 8 的水平线，从坐标 (7, i) 开始。
Why are we drawing a line of length 8?
我们为什么要画一条长度为 8 的线？
That's because it's the width of the rectangle.
那是因为它是矩形的宽度。
So we can go ahead and call this width.
因此，我们可以继续调用这个宽度。
This way, we will be able to use our algorithm for
这样，我们将能够使用我们的算法来处理
rectangles of different sizes.
不同大小的矩形。
And why are we starting at the x location 7?
为什么我们要从 x 位置 7 开始？
Because that's our beginning x coordinate.
因为那是我们的起点 x 坐标。
So we can call that x.
所以我们可以称之为 x。
This way our algorithm will accommodate all values of x.
这样我们的算法就可以容纳 x 的所有值。
Now this part seems a little bit complicated.
现在这部分看起来有点复杂。
We're going to draw a horizontal line of length width, starting at (x,i).
我们将画一条长度为宽度的水平线，从 (x, i) 开始。
It's actually fine for this step to seem a little bit complicated.
这个步骤看起来有点复杂实际上是可以的。
We'll just call that a different programming problem.
我们称之为不同的编程问题。
We're going to assume that we either already know how to
我们假设我们要么已经知道如何
draw a horizontal line of length width starting at (x, i).
画一条长度为 (x, i) 的水平线。
Or we can solve this as its own programming problem,
或者我们可以把它当作自己的编程问题来解决，
beginning with steps 1 through 4 all over again.
从第 1 步到第 4 步重新开始。
For this exercise we're just going to assume we know how to perform this step.
在本练习中，我们假设我们知道如何执行此步骤。
The last thing we want to do,is add a little bit more precision
我们要做的最后一件事就是增加一点精度，
because we wanted the line to be blue.
因为我们希望线条是蓝色的。
So our algorithm needs to specifically say that we are drawing a blue line of length
因此，我们的算法需要特别说明我们正在画一条长度为
width, starting at the location (x,i).
宽度的蓝线，从位置 (x, i) 开始。
Test this algorithm for yourself.
亲自测试这个算法。
Give yourself a value of x, y, a width and
给自己一个
a height that you want to test out and see whether this works for you.
你想要测试的 x、y、宽度和高度的值，看看这是否适合你。
As a final note, some values of x, y, width and
最后一点，x、y、宽度和
height will cause you to draw off the grid.
高度的某些值会导致你画出网格。
In this case we're going to assume that nothing special happens and
在这种情况下，我们将假设没有发生任何特别
that doing nothing in response to this, is the desired behavior.
的事情，并且对此不采取任何措施是理想的行为。
Later on we'll look at ways of handling errors and
稍后我们将探讨以
corner cases in a more sophisticated manner.
更复杂的方式处理错误和极端情况的方法。